Strassberg, Richard, Collection of ILR Buffalo Extension Web Exhibit Files /4267
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Richard Strassberg Collection of ILR Buffalo Extension Web Exhibit Files
2002-2003
[2003]
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Strassberg, Richard
/4267
1.22 cubic feet
1.2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Contains research files in a variety of formats for a web exhibit on Buffalo, NY and Erie County, NY labor history.
8072109
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 02, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Richard Strassberg was Associate Director of the Martin P. Catherwood Library and as Director of the Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives. He held the position of the Director of the Archives from 1978-2007 and was appointed Associate Catherwood Director in 1980.
Following internships at the Colorado State Archives in 1966 and the Colorado State Historical Society in 1967, he was hired as Assistant Archivist for Technical Processes in Cornell's Department of Regional History and University Archives in 1968. In 1970, he was appointed the Technical Processes Coordinator for the department. In 1971, Richard joined the staff of the Labor-Management Documentation Center as its Associate Archivist and moved to his present position as Director of the Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives in 1977. (The Center was renamed in 1995.) The Kheel Center is among the leading repositories of its kind in North America.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4283: ILR School Extension Division (Buffalo, N.Y.) Files
Scope and Contents
The Richard Strassberg Collection of ILR Buffalo Extension Web Exhibit Files, 1984-2003 (bulk 2003), contains research files for a web exhibit on Buffalo, NY and Erie County, NY labor history. The exhibit was hosted on both the District Office and the Kheel Center's websites and was intended to serve as a prototype for similar web exhibits on local NY labor history. Material gathered for the exhibit was used to create a brief essay on local labor history and a chronology of events targeted to a secondary school audience. The collection contains research files and photocopies of sources referenced and correspondence about the project. Material of note includes photocopies of the Buffalo Union Leader (1939-1944), which includes cartoons and clippings on black unions, the CIO, and women workers.
Strassberg, Richard
8072109
- Buffalo, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Missing Pages from Illustrated History of the United Trades and Labor Council of Erie County (1897), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Buffalo Project, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  1 floppy disc
- Dana Ford (tex1) .txt (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Illustrated History of the United Trades and Labor Council, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Rise of the CIO in Buffalo, NY, 1936-1942 photocopied dissertation, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Buffalo Labor History Project- Web Page, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  1 CD; PDF Files
- Buffalo Project, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Illustrated History of the United Trades and Labor Council, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Erie County CD (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Richard Strassberg pulled from drive.
- Marie Sachmowitz cassette, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)